TYLER WISEMAN

Richmond, VA
GitHub | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Data Analyst with three years of experience in libraries, museums, and higher education. Passionate about data stewardship, data accessibility, and data's influence on public policy. My professional background has taught me the critical importance of documentation for data retrieval and how to balance attention to detail with the big picture to tell an accurate and compelling story.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages | SQL, Python, JavaScript (D3.js)

Environments | Excel, Tableau, Visual Studio Code, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MongoDB

EXPERIENCE

Boatwright Library

University of Richmond | Richmond, VA

User Support Specialist

Jul 2019 - Present

- Leverage advanced Excel techniques and queries to investigate and correct library data inconsistencies
- Decreased turn around on replacement copies of missing items by creating a monthly reporting process using system analytics
- Perform technical writing to document internal work processes and provide instructions for library users and employees
- Represent Access Services team on cross-departmental task force to test and customize public facing search interface
- Coach and mentor designated student staff through continuous technical training and conduct performance reviews

The Valentine

History Museum | Richmond, VA

Neighborhood Tour Guide

Aug 2018 - Present

- Engage a diverse audience on walking tours of historic districts that explore the impact of our past on our present
- Updated flagship tour with new standardized route, content, and name leading to 75% attendance increase for the season

Archives Assistant

Jun 2017 – Apr 2019

- Increased online accessibility of 1500+ historic documents by creating finding aids in collections management system
- Contributed to large-scale collection reassessment project by researching provenance of items recommended for deaccession

Institute for Contemporary Art

Virginia Commonwealth University | Richmond, VA

Visitor Experience Associate

Mar 2018 - Jul 2019

- Standardized front desk procedures during institution's first year
- Collaborated with education department on data collection used for program assessment

Lucy's

Restaurant | Richmond, VA

Bar Manager

Nov 2016 – Nov 2018

Can Can Brasserie

Restaurant | Richmond, VA

Bartender/Private Dining Lead

Jun 2012 - Sep 2016

PROJECTS

Know Your Congress | App

Web app exploring the House of Representatives using ProPublica Congress API, Python, MongoDB, D3.is, Tableau

Coronary Heart Disease Prediction | Repo

Collaborative machine learning project using a Random Forest classifier to predict 10-year risk of CHD from Kaggle dataset

Weather Analysis | Website

• Statistical analysis and plots using the OpenWeather API, Pandas, and Jupyter Notebooks

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts | Virginia Commonwealth University

Aug 2010 - Dec 2014

Double Major in International Studies & History with Social Justice concentration

Coding Boot Camp | University of Richmond

Jan 2020 – Jul 2020

Data Analytics & Visualization